# **KYLAN THOMSON**

757-903-1915 | info@kylanthomson.dev | Poulsbo, WA | LinkedIn.com/kylanthomson

#### PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a Full Stack Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience in developing web applications and software solutions. I have extensive knowledge in JavaScript, CSS, React, jQuery, Java, and SQL Server. I have experience in developing web applications from the ground up, as well as troubleshooting and debugging existing applications. I am extremely organized and have a passion for developing creative and efficient solutions to complex problems. I am confident that I can make a positive contribution to XYZ.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML, Node, MongoDB, RESTful APIs, Git, Agile Methodologies, AWS, Object-Oriented Design, Responsive Web Design, Unit Testing, Troubleshooting, Debugging

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Credera (Jan 2022 - Present):

## **Software Engineer**

- Developed, tested, and maintained software applications in Java and AWS using Terraform and Azure
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to create quality solutions and integrate them with SQL databases
- Built automated test scripts to ensure that the software was functioning correctly
- Performed integration testing and identified and resolved issues quickly and efficiently

#### **UNO (Dec 2020 – Feb 2022):**

## **Software Engineer**

- Developed custom client dashboard using React, HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, Redux and design patterns.
- Utilized serverless architecture to refactor existing codebase, improving performance and scalability.
- Built and maintained unit, integration and end-to-end tests to identify and fix bugs.
- Collaborated with other engineers to ensure code was optimized and up-to-date.
- Implemented best practices and standards to ensure high-quality code.

## **EDUCATION**

## Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA

## Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Jan 2016 - May 2021

Coursework: Algorithms & Data Structures, Database Systems, Computer Architecture, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Programming Languages, Web Development, Computer Networks, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Graphics, Computer Security, Human-Computer Interaction, Mobile Application Development, React.js

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Google Cloud Platform Associate (June 2022)
Google Cloud Platform Data Engineering (June 2022)